Finding Aid for the Leo Smit Score Collection, circa 1940-1998
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Leo Smit Score Collection, circa 1940-1998
Mus. Arc. 6.1
Smit, Leo, 1921-1999
18 boxes (185 items)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The collection consists of 123 scores of compositions by Leo Smit, principally in copies of holographs. There are 21 scores of works by other composers arranged or transcribed by Smit. The remaining 41 scores are works by other composers either inscribed to Smit or marked for performance by Smit.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Collection given to the Music Library in 1998 by Leo Smit. Additional items subsequently given by executor of the estate, Nils Vigeland.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
Leo Smit was born to Russian immigrants on January 12, 1921, in Philadelphia. He received his earliest musical training from his father, Kolman Smit, beginning at age five. Kolman Smit was a professional violinist who performed in the Philadelphia Orchestra (1926-1931) under Leopold Stokowski, the Cincinnati Symphony under Fritz Reiner, and the NBC Symphony under Arturo Toscanini.
After private piano studies with Martha Lantner, Joseph Wissof, and Bert Shefter, Smit traveled to Moscow with his mother in 1929 to study piano for three months with Dmitri Kabalevsky on scholarship at the Moscow Conservatory. Upon his return to Philadelphia, Smit received a scholarship in 1930 to study piano at Curtis Institute of Music with noted piano pedagogue Isabelle Vengerova. He continued his studies on scholarship in New York, studying piano with José Iturbi (1933-35) and composition with Nicolas Nabokov (1935). It was under Nabokov's tutelage that Smit produced his first original composition in 1935, Zvay, a song setting of a Yiddish poem by Mani Loeb for soprano and piano.
Smit began his professional career as a pianist while still in his teens. His first professional engagement was as rehearsal pianist for George Balanchine's American Ballet Company in 1936-37. A year after beginning in this position, Smit met Igor Stravinsky during rehearsals of the composer's ballet, Jeu de Cartes. Smit gave his debut recital as a solo pianist at Carnegie Hall in February 1939. His successful debut was followed by a concert tour of the United States in 1940.
Leo Smit's career as composer, pianist, conductor, and educator spanned seven decades of musical life in the United States. He established close working relationships, and/or friendships, with many of the most prominent musicians of the 20th century, including Igor Stravinsky, Béla Bartók, Aaron Copland, Leonard Bernstein, Harold Shapero, William Schuman, Alex Haieff, Leopold Stokowski, and Lukas Foss. As a performer, Smit was an enthusiastic and persuasive advocate and interpreter of the music of his time, especially the solo piano music of Aaron Copland. His compositional output totals more than one hundred works, including two operas, three symphonies, more than ninety songs, two ballets, and numerous chamber and piano works.
Smit was also a talented photographer. In addition to the many photographs he took of noted musicians, Smit also used his skill as a photographer to capture images from his travels. Many of his travel pictures reflect his reverence for nature. As part of his innovative approach to programming, Smit would often include displays of his photography in his theme-based concerts.
During his career Leo Smit earned several awards and honors, including Fulbright (piano) and Guggenheim (composition) Fellowships in 1950, a fellowship at the American Academy in Rome for 1950-51, the Boston Symphony Merit Award in 1953 for his Symphony No. 1 (premiered October 16, 1953 by the Boston Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Charles Munch), the New York Critics Circle Award in 1957 (also for his Symphony No. 1), his selection as an artist for a State Department concert tour of Latin America in 1967-68, and the Buffalo Evening News Man of the Year award in 1969. As an educator, Smit held positions at Sarah Lawrence College (1947-49), UCLA (1957-63), and the State University of New York at Buffalo (1962-84).
Leo Smit died December 12, 1999 in Scripps Hospital, Encinitas, California.
Scope and Content Note
The Leo Smit Score Collection consists of 123 scores of compositions by Leo Smit, principally in copies of holographs. There are 21 scores of works by other composers arranged or transcribed by Smit. The remaining 41 scores are works by other composers either inscribed to Smit or marked for performance by Smit.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in seven series:
I. Compositions by Leo Smit
II. Arrangements and editions of works by other composers
III. Compositions by other composers marked for performance by Leo Smit
IV. Scores by other composers with inscriptions to Leo Smit
V. Scores autographed by Leo Smit.
VI. Assorted scores received with the collection
VII. Additional scores received after original processing was completed
Container List
- Compositions by Leo Smit, 1943-1998, I; Item 1-104
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 ABA: for clarinet (B♭) and piano: 1943 1985, 1 manuscript score (10 pages); 36 cm (Box 1, Item 001)
    Holograph (Photocopy).
    Title page bears 1987 copyright stamp.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 ABA: for clarinet (Bb) and piano: 1943 1985, 1 manuscript score (10 leaves); 28 cm (Box 1, Item 002)
    "ABA is the form of the piece"--Inscription on t.p.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Academic graffiti (1982) Academic graffiti: for (histrionic) voice, clarinet, violoncello, piano and percussion: 1962-82 1982, 1 manuscript score (19 pages); 37 cm (Box 1, Item 003)
    Score marked for performance; also marked with changes.
    Musical additions on manuscript inserts attached.
    "Rental library, Carl Fischer, Inc."--Label on title page.
    "1161"--Label on cover.
    "For Lukas Foss"--Caption.
    Contents: Title -- Henry Adams -- Queen Mary -- G.F. Handel -- Nietzsche -- Xantippe -- Karl Marx -- James Watt -- Kierkegaard -- Kant -- Robert Liston -- Mallarmé.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Academic graffiti (1982). Mallarmé Academic graffiti. 1982, 1 manuscript score (pages 17-19); 34-36 cm (Box 1, Item 004)
    Holograph (Pencil).
    For voice, clarinet, violoncello, piano and percussion.
    "9/7/82 Buffalo, N.Y."--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Alabaster chambers: 1989: seven threnodies for string orchestra 1989, 1 manuscript score (19 pages); 28 cm; Alternate title: Seven threnodies for string orchestra (Box 1, Item 005)
    "In memory of a great artist and a beloved friend Jan DeGaetani."
    "Alabaster Chambers (1989) is a transformation for string orchestra of some of my choruses and songs, inspired by the stupendous poetic visions of Emily Dickinson"--Composer's note, 1991, inserted.
    Duration: circa 15:00.
    Contents: I. Reverential: And kiss the hills, for me, just once--Then--I am ready to go! (3:20) -- II. Agitated: Dying! Dying in the night! (1:35) -- III. Lyrical: We speculated fair, upon every subject, but the grave (2:20) -- IV. Intense: Go boldly--for thou paid'st his price (1:50) -- V. Flowing: There--where she--rested--last (2:45) -- VI. Dramatic: Departed to the judgement (2:20) -- VII. Calm: I have no life but this (1:25).
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Alabaster chambers: (1989): seven threnodies for string orchestra 1989, 1 manuscript score (27 [i.e. 32] pages); 28 cm; Alternate title: Seven threnodies for string orchestra (Box 1, Item 006)
    Pages 24, 25 marked with changes.
    "In memory of a beloved friend, Jan DeGaetani."
    Movements 1, 2, 4, 5, 6, 7, paged continuously; mvt. 3 paged separately, 1-5.
    "Five threnodies"--T.p.; "five" changed to "seven."
    "Alabaster Chambers (1989) is a transformation for string orchestra of some of my choruses and songs, inspired by the stupendous poetic visions fo Emily Dickinson"--C.f. composer's note in final version of score, 1991.
    Contents: I. Reverential: Goodbye to the life I used to live (8/8/89) -- II. Agitated: Dying! Dying in the night! (8/24/89) -- III. Lyrical -- IIII. Intense: Go boldly--for thou paid'st his price (8/24/89) -- V. Moving: There--where she--rested--last (8/28/89) -- VI. Dramatic: Departed--to the judgement (10/24/89) -- VI. Calm: The realm of you.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Alabaster chambers: seven threnodies for string orchestra: 1989 1990, 1 manuscript score (19 pages); 41 cm; Alternate title: Seven threnodies for string orchestra Alternate title: Alabaster chambers for string orchestra (Box 1, Item 007)
    Score bears Theodore Presser copyright stamp in caption.
    Score marked with changes.
    "In memory of a great artist and a beloved friend, Jan DeGaetani."
    "Alabaster Chambers (1989) is a transformation for string orchestra of some of my choruses and songs, inspired by the stupendous poetic visions of Emily Dickinson"--C.f. composer's note in final version of score, 1991.
    Contents: I. Reverential: And kiss the hills, for me, just once--Then--I am ready to go! -- II. Agitated: Dying! Dying in the night! -- III. Lyrical: We speculated fair, upon every subject, but the grave -- IV. Intense: Go boldly--for thou paid'st his price -- V. Flowing: There--where she--rested--last -- VI. Dramatic: Departed to the judgment -- VII. Calm: I have no life but this.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Alchemy of love. Act I. Vocal score The alchemy of love, or, The daemon servant's retribution: a comic opera in three acts. 1960, 1 manuscript vocal score (a-b, 94 pages); 37 cm; Alternate title: Alchemy of love Alternate title: Daemon servant's retribution (Box 1, Item 008)
    Holograph (Ozalid copy).
    Score includes several markings: additions and changes.
    Contents: Introduction -- Scene 1: The alchemist's apartment: the hour of dinner -- Scene 2: General fireball's office; later the same evening.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Alchemy of love. Act I. Vocal score The alchemy of love, or, The daemon servant's retribution: a comic opera in three acts. [Act 1] / libretto by Fred Hoyle 1960, 1 manuscript vocal score (a-b, 94 pages); 37 cm; Alternate title: Alchemy of love Alternate title: Daemon servant's retribution (Box 1, Item 009)
    Bears small number of Smit's markings.
    Contents: Introduction -- Scene 1: The alchemist's apartment: the hour of dinner -- Scene 2: General fireball's office; later the same evening
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Alchemy of love. Act II The alchemy of love: comic opera. 1968, 1 manuscript score (148 pages); 44 cm (Box 2, Item 010)
    Cover title.
    Score marked for performance.
    Pages also numbered 200-347.
    "Dec. 21, 1961"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Alchemy of love. Act II. Vocal score The alchemy of love: a space fable in three acts. 1960, 1 manuscript vocal score (pages 95-172); 37 cm (Box 2, Item 011)
    Title from insert.
    Typescript notes (photocopy, 1 leaf) about the opera inserted.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Alchemy of love. Act II. Vocal score The alchemy of love, or, The daemon servant's retribution: a comic opera in three acts. 1960, 1 manuscript vocal score (pages 95-172); 37 cm; Alternate title: Alchemy of love Alternate title: Daemon servant's retribution (Box 2, Item 012)
    Marked with performance indications and changes.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Alchemy of love. Act II. Vocal score The alchemy of love]. 1960, 1 manuscript vocal score (pages 95-172); 37 cm (Box 2, Item 013)
    Caption title.
    Marked with performance indications, changes, and metronome markings.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Alchemy of love. Selections Four alchemy marches: according to Hoyle, Fred: for orchestra 1972, 1 manuscript score (a-c, 36 pages); 43 cm; Alternate title: Alchemy marches (Box 2, Item 014)
    "Four kookaburra marches"--Caption of composer's notes, p. c.
    "The music of the Four kookaburra marches is taken from my opera, The laughing kookaburras, a space fable with libretto by Sir Fred Hoyle ..."--Composer's note.
    "Feb. 7, 1972"--Colophon.
    Contents: The messenger's march [from Act I] -- The jailor's march [from Act III?]-- General fireball's march [from Act I] -- The love march [from Act II].
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Alone :for female viola-reciter 1988, 1 score (4 leaves); 28 cm (Box 2, Item 015)
    Computer-notated score.
    "For Tina Pelikan"--Caption.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Antiphonies. Selections Antiphonies :for solo violin: 1993 1993, 4 pages of manuscript music; 36 cm (Box 3, Item 016)
    Incomplete score.
    "For Veronika Macchia."
    Duration: circa 6:00.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 At the corner of the sky :for chorus of men and boys (or women) with solo flute, oboe, and speaker 1981, 1 score (24 pages); 36 cm (Box 3, Item 017)
    Includes composer's note.
    Includes piano part for rehearsal only.
    "Complimentary Reference Copy."
    "Poems of North American Indians, edited and translated by Jerome Rothenburg"--C.f. caption, Carl Fischer published score (New York: 1981).
    ""A" on tape, Counter #000 beginning."
    Contents: Vision event I (Sioux) -- Lullaby (Tsimshian) -- Interlude -- Mourning song (Tsimshian) -- Animal song 1: Turkey (Navajo) -- Animal song 2: Deer (Yuma) -- Animal song 3: Coyote (Nez Percé) -- Animal song 4: Wolf (Sioux) -- Vision event 3 (Eskimo) -- Song of an initiate (Huichol).
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Attacca lo scherzo :for piano solo: 1984 1984, 8 pages of manuscript music; 42 cm (Box 3, Item 018)
    Holograph (pencil and ink).
    "1.30.84"--Colophon.
    "First draft."
    "Commissioned by and dedicated to Yvar Mikhashoff."
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Birthday pieces Two birthday pieces for [blank] 1994, 1 manuscript score (2 leaves); 28 cm (Box 3, Item 019)
    Holograph (photocopy).
    "In friendship and with love, from Leo--July 4, 1994, Garth Newel, VA."
    Contents: Happy birthday duo for violin and cello (July 4, 1994, Garth Newel, VA.) -- Happy birthday chorale for string quartet (July 4, 1994, Garth Newel, VA.).
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Caedmon. Vocal score Caedmon: cantata for 3 solo voices, male chorus and orchestra: 1952/70 1970, 1 manuscript vocal score (60 pages); 36 cm (Box 3, Item 020)
    Includes insert: Acrostic poem to St. Caedmon.
    Text mostly in English; opening chorus in Latin.
    Acc. originally for orchestra.
    "Rome 1952/Malibu 1970"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Canon super nomen Bach :[for string quartet: 1985] 1985, 4 manuscript parts; 32 cm (Box 3, Item 021)
    "2/2/85"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Canon super nomen Bach; arranged Canon super nomen Bach :for saxophone quartet: 1987 1987, 1 manuscript score (3 leaves); 36 cm (Box 3, Item 022)
    Originally for string quartet.
    "October 6, 1987"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Canticle prelude, no. 5 Canticle prelude 5 :for organ 198-?, 4 pages of manuscript music; 28 cm; Alternate title: Canticle prelude no. 5 (Box 3, Item 023)
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Capriccio, string orchestra Capriccio for string orchestra :1958 1958, 1 manuscript score (45 pages); 36 cm (Box 3, Item 024)
    Composer's note on prefatory page.
    "Composed for Aaron Copland, in memory of Peter Ilytch Tchaikovsky"--Composer's note.
    "The Capriccio for string orchestra was first performed at the Ojai Festival in 1958, Aaron Copland conducting"--Composer's note.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 A choir of starlings: a serenata for four voices and ten instruments 1951, 1 score (107 pages); 36 cm (Box 3, Item 025)
    For 4 voices (SATB), with 2 oboes, bassoon, 2 horns, 2 violins, viola, violoncello, and double bass.
    "To Isabel and Laurence Roberts."
    Publisher no. from label on cover: 1296.
    "Property of Carl Fischer, Inc ..."--Stamp on title page.
    Duration: 30:00.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Choir of starlings. Vocal score A choir of starlings: vocal score 1951, 1 manuscript vocal score (76 leaves); 27-28 cm (Box 3, Item 026)
    Title from folder cover.
    Manuscript (Photocopy).
    Inserted: Lenten is come: a round for four-part chorus of female, male or mixed voices a cappella / poem by Anthony Hecht; [music by] Leo Smit. New York: C. Fischer, c1977. Pl. no. N6118. (pages 2-11).
    Page 46 photocopied backwards.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Choir of starlings. Vocal score. Selections A choir of starlings 1951, 1 manuscript vocal score (76); 36 cm (Box 3, Item 027)
    Mvt. II (pages 21-26) wanting.
    Inserted: Photocopy of Lenten is come: a round for four-part chorus of female, male or mixed voices a cappella / poem by Anthony Hecht; [music by] Leo Smit. New York: C. Fischer, c1977. Pl. no. N6118. (pages 2-11).
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Choir of starlings. Vocal score. Selections A choir of starlings: a serenata for four voices and ten instruments 1951, 1 manuscript vocal score (76 leaves); 33 cm (Box 3, Item 028)
    Manuscript (Vellum masters).
    Incomplete: Mvmt VI. (pages 55-62) wanting.
    Acc. arr. for piano.
    Words by Anthony Hecht.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Choir of starlings. Vocal score. Selections A choir of starlings: a serenata for four voices and ten instruments 1951, 1 manuscript vocal score (76 pages); 33 cm (Box 3, Item 029)
    Manuscript (Ozalid copy).
    Incomplete.
    Mvts. II and III (pages 21-38) and mvts. V-VI (pages 49-62) wanting.
    "Return to Boosey & Hawkes hire library."
    "Dec. 3, 1951."
    Contents: I. Invocation to the muse -- IV. Gigue -- VII. Finale.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Christmas tree carols. Vocal score. German & English Three Christmas tree carols :for mixed chorus with eight instruments 1975, 1 vocal score (24 pages); 28 cm (Box 4, Item 030)
    "For Christopher and Eliza Foss"--First page of score.
    In German and English; words also printed as text.
    Based on three pieces from Franz Liszt's Weihnachtsbaum.
    Contents: Old Christmas carol = Altes weihnachtslied -- O holy night = O heilige Nacht -- O come, all ye faithful = Adeste Fideles.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Christmas tree carols. Vocal score. German & English Three Christmas tree carols: altes Weihnachtslied: after Franz Liszt: for mixed chorus and an instrumental ensemble 1974, 1 manuscript vocal score (ii, 32 pages); 36 cm; Alternate title: Altes Weihnachtslied (Box 4, Item 031)
    Includes markings made by Smit; changes and additions.
    "For Christopher and Eliza Foss."
    "May 24, 1974"--Colophon.
    "Carl Fischer sole selling agent"--Cover.
    Words in German & English; also printed as text.
    Duration: 12:00.
    Contents: Altes Weihnachtslied = Old Christmas carol -- O heilige Nacht! = O holy night -- O come all ye faithful = Adeste Fideles.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Christmas tree carols. Old Christmas carol. Vocal score Altes Weihnachtslied =Old Christmas carol 1974?, 1 manuscript vocal score (6 pages); 36 cm; Alternate title: Old Christmas carol Alternate title: Weihnachtsbaum (Box 4, Item 032)
    Based on Altes Weihnachtsbaum, from Liszt's Weihnachtsbaum.
    Includes markings; changes and additions.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Cock robin :for soprano, piccolo (or flute) and percussion 1979, 1 manuscript score (24 pages); 36 cm (Box 4, Item 033)
    Holograph (Ozalid).
    "Corrected."
    "Commissioned by Laurence Trott through the Piccolo Society"--Title page verso.
    Includes markings: changes and additions.
    "22. IX.79"--Colophon.
    "Rental library Carl Fischer"--Sticker on title page.
    "Copied by Nils Vigeland"--Colophon.
    Contents: 1. Sparrow -- 2. Fly -- 3. Fish -- 4. Beetle -- 5. Owl -- 6. Parson -- 7. Lark -- 8. Dove -- 9. Kite -- 10. Thrush -- 11. Bull -- 12. Birds.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Concerto, piano, orchestra Concerto for orchestra and piano 1968?, 14 manuscript parts; 32 cm (Box 4, Item 034)
    Manuscript (Ink on vellum).
    Solo piano part wanting.
    "Master parts"--Envelope.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Concerto, piano, orchestra; arranged Concerto for piano and orchestra :1968 1980, 1 manuscript score ([33] pages); 36-42 cm (Box 4, Item 035)
    Holograph (Ozalid copy & Photocopy).
    "Revised July 17, 1980, Brevard, N.C."--Colophon.
    "Jan. 15, 1980, Solana Beach, Calif."--Colophon.
    Contents: Lento improvisato -- Allegro dramatico -- Adagietto espressivo -- Movimento agitato con cadenza -- Fuga alla marcia -- Allegro finale.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Concerto, piano, orchestra (sketches) Piano concerto between 1968 and 1980, 1 manuscript volumes (various pagings); 36 cm (Box 4, Item 036)
    Includes full and reduced scores.
    "Sketches finale; Sketches 1st mvt (piano solo)."
    Includes three sketches of the finale.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Copernicus: narrative and credo 1973, 1 score (iii, 91 pages); 26 x 32 cm (Box 4, Item 037)
    "Commissioned by the National Academy of Sciences through the Copernicus Society of America, Edward J. Piszek, president, to commemorate the 500th birthday of Nicolaus Copernicus."--Page I.
    Words in English or Latin.
    For four-part chorus of mixed voices, narrator, and instrumental ensemble.
    Duration: circa 25:00.
    "Rental Dept. MCA music"--Cover.
    "March 19, 1973, Roma"--Colophon.
    Contents: Introduction -- The birth -- The uncle (Lucas Watzelrode) -- Cracow student song -- Columbus west -- Italian madrigal -- Sorrow and solitude -- The Teutonic War -- Papal disputation -- The book -- The death -- Laudemus -- Credo.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Dance card; arranged Dance card :for orchestra 198-, 1 manuscript score (73 pages); 33 cm (Box 4, Item 038)
    Originally for piano.
    Pages 43-45 blank.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Delaunay pochoirs (1980) =Delaunay stencils: troix morceaux pour violoncelle et piano 1980, 1 manuscript score (17 pages) + 1 manuscript part; 36 cm; Alternate title: Delaunay stencils (Box 4, Item 039)
    "À Frances-Marie Uitti et Yvar Mikhashoff."
    Contents: Pochoir Russe (Sonia Delaunay) -- Pochoir en jazz (Charles Delaunay) -- Pochoir aux fenêtres (Robert Delaunay).
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 The dwarf heart :soprano + piano: six songs 1987, 1 manuscript score (40 pages); 36 cm (Box 4, Item 040)
    "Six songs"--T.p.; "six" changed to "five."
    "Dec. 3, 1987"--Colophon.
    Duration: circa 23:00.
    Contents: The kiss -- How we danced -- Eighteen days without you (December 15) -- Seven times (from the death baby) -- The ambition bird -- Ringing the bells.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Ecstatic pilgrimage. Celestial thrush The celestial thrush (1988): a cycle of twelve songs about music and birds: for soprano and piano 1988, 1 score (59 pages); 36 cm (Box 5, Item 041)
    Cycle 2 from the Ecstatic Pilgrimage.
    Duration: circa 21:30.
    Contents: I was a phoebe (9/13/88) -- The bird her punctual music brings (10/7/88) -- The earth has many keys (10/6/88) -- The bobolink is gone (9/22/88) -- A train went through a burial gate (10/5/88) -- I cannot dance upon my toes (10/4/88) -- Upon his saddle sprung a bird (10/2/88) -- Better--than music! (10/2/88) -- Bind me--I still can sing (9/28/88) -- Within my garden, rides a bird (9/28/88) -- Heart, not so heavy as mine (9/25/88) -- I shall keep singing! (9/28/88).
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Ecstatic pilgrimage. Celestial thrush The celestial thrush :twelve songs about birds and music: for mezzo-soprano (or soprano) and piano 1996, 1 score (43 leaves); 28 cm (Box 5, Item 042)
    Computer notated score.